[
  {
    "question": "Which of the following themes do contemporary artists tend to dramatize within environmentalist works?",
    "a": "pollution",
    "b": "wildlife conservation",
    "c": "urbanization",
    "d": "overpopulation",
    "e": "deforestation",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Agnes Denes artwork involved her working with a two-acre plot of wheat?",
    "a": "Wheatfield—A Confrontation",
    "b": "Caribou Migration I",
    "c": "Offshore Drilling",
    "d": "Tree Mountain",
    "e": "Rice/Tree/Burial",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which historical event inspired the sculptures featured in Noah Purifoy’s 66 Signs of Neon?",
    "a": "the Pulaski Riot",
    "b": "the Stonewall Uprising",
    "c": "the Watts Rebellion",
    "d": "the Detroit Race Riot",
    "e": "the Rodney King Riots",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following museums houses Noah Purifoy’s Offshore Drilling?",
    "a": "the Outdoor Desert Museum",
    "b": "the Heard Museum",
    "c": "the Louvre",
    "d": "the Metropolitan Museum of Art",
    "e": "the National Gallery of Art",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Within his “Paintings of Garbage” series, Vik Muniz put a new spin on",
    "a": "Girl with a Pearl Earring",
    "b": "The Night Watch",
    "c": "Mona Lisa",
    "d": "The Starry Night",
    "e": "The Birth of Venus",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Subhankar Banerjee’s Caribou Migration I aims to accomplish all of the following goals EXCEPT",
    "a": "protecting the ANWR from oil drilling",
    "b": "influencing perception of the ANWR as a fragile ecosystem",
    "c": "disproving the idea that the ANWR is lifeless",
    "d": "providing evidence of animals’ patterns",
    "e": "promoting tourism in the ANWR",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following events exhibited Agnes Denes’s Wheatfield—A Confrontation?",
    "a": "the Annual Convention on Climate Change and Artivism",
    "b": "the Global Exhibition for Environmental Conservation",
    "c": "the Annual Conference on Renewable Energy and Creativity",
    "d": "the International Art Show for the End of World Hunger",
    "e": "the International Symposium on Sustainable Agriculture",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Noah Purifoy’s Offshore Drilling reflects the oil refinement industry’s disproportionate pollutive effect on",
    "a": "poorer neighborhoods and communities of color",
    "b": "agricultural farmlands and rural communities",
    "c": "coastal regions and marine ecosystems",
    "d": "remote wilderness areas and indigenous communities",
    "e": "dense urban neighborhoods and commercial centers",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Subhankar Banerjee worked in all of the following areas EXCEPT",
    "a": "scientist",
    "b": "advocacy",
    "c": "architecture",
    "d": "scholar",
    "e": "photographer",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which governmental assembly was presented with Subhankar Banerjee's Caribou Migration I?",
    "a": "the United States Senate",
    "b": "the German Bundestag",
    "c": "the European Parliament",
    "d": "the Russian State Duma",
    "e": "the United States House of Representatives",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who inspired Vik Muniz’s Marat (Sebastião)?",
    "a": "Jacques-Louis David",
    "b": "Vincent van Gogh",
    "c": "Frida Kahlo",
    "d": "Pablo Picasso",
    "e": "Jackson Pollock",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these groups aided Muniz and received payment from the auction of his artwork?",
    "a": "wildlife conservationists",
    "b": "farmers",
    "c": "museum curators",
    "d": "local artisans",
    "e": "garbage pickers",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which governmental body did Noah Purifoy join in the 1980s?",
    "a": "National Assembly of State Arts",
    "b": "Minnesota State Arts Board",
    "c": "National Endowment for the Arts",
    "d": "Oregon Arts Commission",
    "e": "California Arts Council",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does documentary photography MOST influence environmentalist art?",
    "a": "showcasing the possibilities of sustainable urban design",
    "b": "arguing for the preservation of undeveloped lands",
    "c": "capturing the biodiversity of untouched natural habitats",
    "d": "recording the environmental damages of pollution and extraction",
    "e": "chronicling the development of renewable energy technologies",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What medium does Vik Muniz use to present his artworks?",
    "a": "performance art",
    "b": "photography",
    "c": "computer software",
    "d": "sculpture",
    "e": "oil on canvas",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  }
]